theidearoom.net 2019-07-15

# PRIVACY POLICY - The Idea Room

* _updated May 21, 2018_

By continuing to use this website, you agree to the updated [**Terms of Use**](https://www.theidearoom.net/terms-of-use/) and consent to the collection, use, disclosure and transfer of information as described in this updated Privacy Policy. Please note that you are accessing a site which is designed for and targeted to U.S. audiences and is governed by and operated in accordance with U.S. laws.

## **WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?**

We collect information from you when you buy a product from us, subscribe to our email list or leave a comment on our website.

When ordering, registering or leaving a comment on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your: name or e-mail address.

## **HOW WILL WE USE YOUR INFORMATION?**

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  * To improve customer service and respond to questions

(your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs)

  * To process transactions

Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your consent, other than for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested.

  * If you have given consent, we send periodic emails

The email address you provide for order processing, may be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order, in addition to receiving occasional company news, updates, related product or service information, etc.

Note: If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.

## **HOW WILL WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION?**

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, **** we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.  We do not share information with third parties or store any information.

After a transaction, your private information (credit cards, social security numbers, financials, etc.) will not be stored on our servers but through PayPal’s online services.

I you reside in Europe, we comply with the EU General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR).

## **ADVERTISING PRIVACY STATEMENT.**

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site.  AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

## **DO WE USE COOKIES?**

Yes. A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.  Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

## **FOR EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA RESIDENTS.**

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.  If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact AdThrive at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#325b5c545d725356465a405b44571c515d5f). If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences icon. (Available in the EU.)

## **WE DO NOT DISCLOSE INFORMATION TO OUTSIDE PARTIES.**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety.

## **CHILDRENS ONLINE PRIVACY PROTECTION ACT COMPLIANCE.**

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.

## **LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES.**

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

## **OPT OUT.  **

You can opt out at anytime by clicking the unsubscribe link on the periodic emails and newsletters.

## **PROMOTIONS.**

This blog accepts forms of cash advertising, sponsorship, paid insertions or other forms of compensation.

The compensation received may influence the content selected to publish and the timing of that post. That content, advertising space or post will be identified as such within the guidelines of the FTC disclosure rules.

The views and opinions expressed on this blog are purely the bloggers’ own. Any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider or party in question.

We won’t promote things we don’t believe in…it just is too hard to write something convincing in that case. We turn down more opportunities than we take because we know that our audience relies on our opinion and what we write about becomes a recommendation.

## **AFFILIATE LINKS.**

We occasionally use affiliate links.  I might get a small commission if you purchase from my link.  There is no additional cost to you AT ALL.  I only provide information for products I believe in, purchase myself and feel comfortable promoting.  It’s not worth it to me to “make a quick buck.”  I want you to know that when I promote something it’s because I genuinely love it and use it.

This blog abides by word of mouth marketing standards. I believe in honesty of relationship, opinion and identity. The compensation received may influence the advertising content, topics or posts made in this blog. That content, advertising space or post will be clearly identified as paid or sponsored content.

## **TERMS AND CONDITIONS.**

Please also visit our [Terms and Conditions](https://www.theidearoom.net/terms-of-use/) section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website here.

## **CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY.**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, and/or update the Privacy Policy modification date below.

**Last updated May 21, 2018**

## **CONTACT US.**

If you have any questions regarding this or if you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please don’t hesitate to email Amy: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or through this contact form [here](https://www.theidearoom.net/contact/).

### JOIN OUR NEWSLETTER

**********Would you like more Recipes, DIY, Printables and Organization Ideas?**

* * *

 **Subscribing to the newsletter will enable us to periodically send you creative content exclusively for Idea Room subscribers.**

***View our Privacy Policy**[ **here**](https://www.theidearoom.net/disclosure-policy/) **.**
